TRICIA NORRIS, MBA, CSPO, CSM

5816 E Rois Rd. | Richmond, VA 23227 (804) 614-6547 tricianorris97@gmail.com

LinkedIn: www.linkedin.com/in/tricianorris
Github: https://github.com/plnorris97

Portfolio: https://plnorris97.github.io/tricia-norris-portfolio

Professional Summary

Full Stack Web Developer with a background in marketing and life-long dedication to learning and professional improvement. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Proficient in collaborating with project stakeholders, vendors and clients while using Agile methodologies.

Expertise & Skills

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery, Moment.js, MySQL, CLI, Bootstrap, Github, Agile Scrum, Project Management, Adobe CQ5, Adobe Creative Cloud, Web Strategy, Email Marketing, Oracle® Eloqua, Wordpress, Analytics Reporting

Professional Experience

Talking Monkey Media

July 2018-Present

Marketing Manager

- Manage relationships with small business and non-profit clients
- Provide project management for website clients coordinating between designers and developers
- Direct and manage social media campaigns including planning, scheduling, designing social media brand

Norris Consulting, LLC

March 2016-November 2018

Principal, Head Marketer

- Connect small businesses with creatives resources
- · Provide marketing project management support for new and existing marketing plans
- · Build comprehensive, multi-channel strategies using digital, traditional and inbound tactics

Capital One (Profiles)

June 2016-December 2017

Marketing Manager

- Develop and implement annual strategies for trade show and sales channels
- Manage team projects in a cross-functional agile environment
- Refine existing processes with other functional teams
- Partner with Affiliates client development team to identify synergies in strategy and execution

Genworth Financial

December 2011-April 2016

Marketing Specialist

- Supported the life and annuity product lines for 25 internal/external wholesalers & 12 individual products
- Led improvement of relationship between Marketing and Web/IT teams (2014-2015) reducing request turnaround from 1-2 weeks to 1-3 days improving speed to market
- Product owner/web content manager for 4 websites (producer and consumer)
- Launched B2B website A (2014) collaborating with teams of developers, UX, design, research, analytics and stakeholders; 73 components and pages; policy illustrations increased 77%; material downloads increased 5%; Time On Site increased 3%
- Launched B2B website B (2015) collaborating with teams of developers, UX, design, research, analytics and stakeholders; 86 components and pages; Developed Product Selector feature
- Maintained website backlogs (~10 active items/month) and test plans for iteration on web properties
- Managed website subscription email sent to members; increased email click-to-open rate 7.4% YOY
- Assisted in day to day management of Edward Jones annuity relationship (2011-2015)

Premier Partners Sales Associate (Retail)

- Provided pre-sales and marketing support to Retail long term care, life and annuity Agents in San Francisco, Los Angeles and San Diego
- Assisted Agents with marketing needs by identifying concepts, sales strategies and fulfillment
- Coordinated Agent drip campaigns targeting clients, prospects and Centers of Influence

Headway Corporate Resources-Genworth

January 2010 - November 2010

Long Term Care Marketing Specialist

- Supported the LTC product line and delivered core marketing & sales concepts to a 20-person Sales team
- Managed 300+ recomply sales pieces in project workflow tool while collaborating with Marketing team
- Maintained inventory of current marketing materials
- Assisted in day to day management of the Edward Jones LTC relationship

Rightminds

November 2009-January 2010

Account Coordinator-Web

- Assisted with account management of new media clients including website user experience and maintenance as well as client communication
- Supported other agency functions as necessary in graphics and art department

Education

Full Stack Web Development Bootcamp, 2019

University of Richmond, Richmond, VA

 An intensive 24-week long boot camp dedicated to designing and building web applications. Skills learned consisted of HTML5, CSS3, Javascript, JQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node JS, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handlebars JS, & React JS.

Masters of Business Administration, 2014

Virginia Commonwealth University, Richmond, VA

International trip: Beijing and Shanghai, China

Bachelor of Arts, Spanish and International Studies (Latin America), 1997

Elon University, Elon, NC

• Study abroad: Ecuador (Spring 1997) and Costa Rica (Winter 1995)

Certifications

- Certified Scrum Product Owner® '15, ScrumAlliance.org, Lic. 512888
- Certified Scrum Master, '16, ScrumAlliance.org, Lic. 582143
- Certified Direct Marketer, Interactive Marketing Institute, '08

Awards

- Marketing Automation, Genworth, '12
- Three Point Star Award for Commitment to Superior Service, LandAmerica '06